Sunny Singh

me@sunnysingh.io | (516) 537-8258 | Gastonia, NC

Summary

Experienced and passionate web developer with extensive programming and web design skills. I am constantly exploring new technologies in the industry for creating efficient, secure, and pleasant-to-use websites and web applications.

Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Node.js, PHP, SQL/MySQL, Java

Libraries & Frameworks: React, Redux, Laravel, WordPress, Bootstrap, jQuery, Angular (v1), Sass, PostCSS

Software & Tools: Bash, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Vagrant, Postman, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch 2

Experience

Fit to Rent, Inc.
Front End Developer
May 2016 - Present
http://www.fit2rent.com

A service to help responsible tenants meet trustworthy landlords. Built the marketing site, blog, and web apps:

- Converted design mockups from Photoshop to coded website for the marketing site. Used common technologies (HTML, CSS/Less, JS/jQuery, Bootstrap).
- Built the blog with WordPress and a custom theme. Posts from the blog were also fetched via an API for integration into the marketing site. Used localStorage for caching posts on marketing site.
- Launched a full redesign of the marketing site in two weeks.
- Built both web apps for the landlord and tenant services. Data was fetched from a JSON API via the Ajax fetch() browser API. Used modern JavaScript libraries including React, Redux, and Redux Form.
- Used the Stripe and Dwolla JavaScript APIs for credit card and ACH payments and security deposits.
- Built a user messaging UI which included landlords being able to message multiple tenants and users.
- Built a notification system to poll the backend for new alerts, but only if the user was active on the page.
- Solved numerous issues and edge cases through testing and user feedback.
- Improved performance of both marketing website and web apps. Used a Node.js module to convert marketing site to static files. Implemented Gzip compression for web app JS and CSS bundles.

Ninjality
Co-founder, Lead Developer
January 2014 - Present
http://ninjality.com

A web design agency I run. I worked on multiple internal and client projects including:

- A redesign for <u>digitalbounds.com</u>, a technology blog. Built a custom WordPress theme that focused on content. Included custom widgets to display ads and identify featured posts from the admin.
- Web app for <u>codebee.io</u>, a social network for developers and designers. Back-end written in Laravel, and front-end UI with Bootstrap. Utilized Node.js, Redis, and Socket.IO for real-time capabilities.

- Open source project http://socialshar.es. I wrote it to help other developers fix privacy and performance issues on the web by writing a common set of share buttons. Code on GitHub: http://git.io/socialshares
- Open source project http://devne.ws. I wanted an easier way to read Hacker News, GitHub Trends, and Product Hunt without visiting each website individually. Wrote front-end React app to aggregate all three via APIs and page crawling. Code on GitHub: http://git.io/devnews
- Website and mobile app for finding businesses within resort locations. Involved building a location finder, listing search, and admin dashboard for business owners. API created with Laravel, which was used by the Angular front-end for the website, and lonic for the mobile app.

WIX Filters
Web Marketing, Web Development
June 2012 - August 2016
Gastonia, NC

- Saved the company thousands of dollars by converting the website's timeline module from Flash to JS.
- Edited product images with Adobe Photoshop by removing backgrounds, adjusting color and saturation, cropping, and exporting to various sizes and formats
- Managed store locations for the website with Microsoft Access database software.
- Managed users for the online training program, WIX eLearning.

Personal Website August 2011 - Present http://sunnysingh.io

Portfolio-style website to display my skills, projects, articles, and contact information. Recently redesigned with:

- A responsive layout with CSS Flexbox.
- Static site/blog generator called Metalsmith, written in Node.js.
- PostCSS, Webpack, and Babel build tools for processing modern CSS and JS feature sets.
- Optimized performance (96+ ranking in Google Page Speed).

Relevant Experience STARS Program Charlotte, NC

Part of a volunteer STARS program at UNC Charlotte. Was given leadership roles in assisting students to learn coding fundamentals such as logic truth tables and basic HTML/CSS.

Education

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Degree: B.A. in Computer Science Concentration: Web Development

References are available upon request.